ADAM KIM

SEC+ | CYSA+ | CSAP

Tenacious IT professional with over 3 years of experience in various areas of technology. Progressing from audio visual to network IT, with recent exposures to work exclusively on cybersecurity policies from planning to publication, assessing security postures, and deployment of a SOC launch. Ascertained expanded knowledge in cybersecurity, network/desktop, and programming to target and resolve complex security challenges. Seeking to implement knowledge from cyber certifications and training to become your next cybersecurity professional.

Contact

Akim456@gmail.com

AtomKim.com

**** 347-554-3119

in AdamKim456

Resv

Certifications

CompTIA

Security+

CySA+

CSAP

<u>A+</u>

Microsoft

AZ-900

Cisco

Cyber Security Essentials
Networking Essentials
Linux Essentials (NDG)

Education

2021

Per Scholas, Bronx NY Cyber Security Analyst

2018

Per Scholas, Bronx NY Java Developer

2015

Queens College, Queens NY

B.A. Media Studies

Employment

Cascade Bicycle Club | Cascade.org

Seattle, WA

Volunteer Cybersecurity Consultant

Oct. 2021 - Current

Objectives to increase current security posture and meet security objectives. From preparation to SOC implementation, a collaborated effort to secure the mission to bring people together to experience the joy of bicycling through transportation, recreation, and friendship.

- Conducted risk & vulnerability assessments of the company security posture
- Advised best practices to operate inline with the NIST framework
- · Conducted research & preparation of security tools to meet company security objectives
- Oversaw installation and testing of a Security Onion & service/plugin integration
- Currently practicing monitoring and fine tuning the SIEM to improve accuracy

The Law Offices of Kim & Associates

Network Engineer

Jan. 2019 - Oct. 2021

Development and maintenance of network infrastructure, prioritized network availability and security for all employees within the company. Reduced network and endpoint issues, increased productivity, strengthened company security posture. Assigned to threat hunt and investigate insider threats. Collaborated directly with the DFS to develop cyber security polices in accordance to 23 NYCRR Part 500(e). Orchestrated business continuity procedures for all technologies within the company during the frequent shifts of the pandemic.

- Redesigned physical and logical design of network infrastructure
- Segmented and maintenance private NAS's and CRM
- Administered user access, subnetting, and static IPs
- Strengthened WAPS securely for employees and limited access to visitors
- · Instructed acceptable use policy and security training
- · Developed automated scripts for employees and increased productivity and office morale
- Centralized endpoint management to monitor malware, unauthorized apps, and updates
- Assembled 25+ desktop PCs, troubleshooting, and responsible for equipment budgeting
- Converted 50+ office & home PCs overnight for remote, day 1 of the pandemic shutdown
- $\bullet \ \, \text{Streamlined configurations for 20+ VoIP/analog phones, 5 printers, CCTV, and peripherals } \\$
- Deployed telepresence systems for 5 conference rooms for court proceedings due to the shift of the pandemic
- Authored the 23 CRR-NY-500(e) cyber security policy to completion for the business, approved by the Department of Financial Services

ADAM KIM

SEC+ | CYSA+ | CSAP

Skills

CYBER SECURITY

Packet Capture Analysis SIEM Security Onion Nmap / Zenmap WAP Security Virtualization Hashing & Encryption Hardening Policies & Compliance

NETWORK

Network Design
NAS & Cloud
Routers / Switches / Hubs
DHCP / Static / Subnetting
Port Forwarding
VoIP / CCTV
MAC Filtering

SOFTWARE

Windows / MAC / Linux VMware Wireshark Packet Tracer Nessus Maltego Itarian & Comodo OBS / NDI / SRT / NGINX

HARDWARE

Building PCs
Routers & Switches
SOHO / Dell Sonic Wall
A/V Telepresence
Device Audit
Imaging / Cloning
Data Backup & Recovery
Secure Destruction

PROGRAMMING

Java, SQL HTML5, CSS BATCH Auto Hot Key AGILE / SDLC / SCRUM Expert Googler

Employment

HSBC Audio Visual Specialist (MSP) Tri-state Oct. 2017 - June 2018

Team lead on multiple audio visual projects for HSBC NYC Headquarters and neighboring branches across the tri-state. Accountable for A/V engineering for international conferences of up to 50 participants at one time, room surveys for Cisco telepresence system integrations, logistics, deploying, configuring, and decommissioning of systems.

- Facilitated multiple ongoing projects simultaneously from start to completion
- Coordinated with other departments such as IT to ensure deliverables were met
- · Projects were completed ahead of schedule while working safely and efficiently
- Responsible for training, delegating assignments, and assessing quality of work
- Monitored broadcasts to deliver high quality, smooth, and efficient teleconferences
- Expert in surveying rooms for telepresence system installations and planning
- Provided white glove customer service and communicated effectively with clients including system training and designing quick reference guides

Law Office of Kwangsoo Kim

Queens, NY

Personal Injury Protection (PIP) Admin Jan. 2015 - Mar. 2017 Expert in NY & NJ PIP / No-Fault procedures. Responsible for over 450 cases in various

expert in NY & NJ PIP / No-Fault procedures. Responsible for over 450 cases in various stages of litigation on the Supreme and Civil Court calendar in all 5 boroughs. Maintained persistent client relations, office administration, legal support for IME, EBT, 50H, and discovery/response.

- No-Fault claims were set up and ensured all No-Fault documents were delivered
- · Assisted clients with lost wages, worker's comp, social security disability claims
- · Maintained all client medical bills and liens to avoid them from going into collections
- Disputed and negotiated all medical bills, liens, and collections
- Prepared documents for arbitration, NF arbitration, and medical summaries
- · Worked in liaison with all departments to ensure our clients had the best outcome at trial
- · Adhered to the rules and regulations of HIPAA compliance

Labs / Activity

Currently learning & practicing with a SIEM to simulate a SOC environment to triage real world cyber threats and remediation. In time, security projects will be published to my <u>portfolio</u>. Often found tinkering on TryHackMe or studying for the Pentest+, CASP+, and CISSP.

- Host Machine Nessus, Maltego, Wireshark, and VMware
- VM 2x Ubuntu, Kali, 2x Win10, Opnsense Firewall, and Security Onion SIEM
- <u>Security Onion</u> TheHive, Playbook, Fleet, osquery, CyberChef, Elasticsearch, Logstash, Kibana, Suricata, Zeek, and Wazuh